Guide to the Kathy Acker Papers, 1972-1997 and undated RL.00011
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Writings
  - Other Writings by Acker, 1972-1994; 2 boxes
    - My Favorite Websites (typescript), 1997 (Box 22, Folder 45)
    - New York: Personal (annotated typescript), undated (Box 22, Folder 46)
    - Nightmare City (annotated typescript), undated (Box 22, Folder 47)
    - Nonpatriarchal Language: The Body (annotated typescripts), undated (Box 22, Folder 48)
    - Nonsense and Sense: New York City (annotated typescript), 1990 (Box 22, Folder 49)
    - O (annotated typescript), undated (Box 22, Folder 50)
    - On Being Asked about 1986 (annotated typescript) (Box 22, Folder 51)
    - One Death of America - Andy Warhol (annotated typescript), undated (Box 22, Folder 52)
    - On Narrative (annotated typescript), 1993 (Box 22, Folder 53)
    - On Twin Peaks (annotated typescript), undated (Box 22, Folder 54)
    - Personal Language Personal History (typescripts), undated (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - A Personal View of the Satanic Verses (typescript), undated (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Peter Gordon: Ambiguity (typescript), 1981 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Pirates (annotated typescript), undated (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Postmodernism (annotated typescript), undated (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Property (annotated typescript), undated (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Psyche (1 notebook, loose notes, typescripts), undated, 2 slides (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - from Psyche's Journal (typescript), 1997 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Psyche's Journal electronic file, 1997; MS Word document extracted from 3.5" floppy disk; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL00011-SET-0002, Disk RL00011-FL3-0001)
    - Raw Heat (annotated typescript), 1977 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Report on the Nineties (typescript), undated (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Representations and Misrepresentations (annotated typescript), undated (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - The Seattle Book (annotated typescript), 1980 (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Sexual Censorship (annotated typescript), 1983 (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - Some American Cities (annotated typescript, typescript), undated (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - Statements on the Nature of Musical Comedy (annotated typescript), 1994 (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - Ten out of Many Women Writers (annotated typescript), undated (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - Theoritcal Language in a Patriarchal Society (typescripts), undated (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - The Thesmophoriazusae (annotated typescript), 1973 (Box 23, Folder 18)
    - Things Left Unsaid: An Interview with Mary Gaitskill (annotated typescript), undated (Box 23, Folder 19)
    - This Story Isn't Written for Females (annotated typescript), undated (Box 23, Folder 20)
    - Three Views of American Reality (annotated typescript), undated (Box 23, Folder 21)
    - The Topic Today I Believe is Censorship (annotated typescript), undated (Box 23, Folder 22)
    - The Travels of the Pirates: These Beginnings (typescript), undated (Box 23, Folder 23)
    - Two Girls Discuss Women (annotated typescript), undated (Box 23, Folder 24)
    - The Underside of Dream (annotated typescript), undated (Box 23, Folder 25)
    - Voodoo (annotated typescript), undated (Box 23, Folder 26)
    - William Burroughs (typescript), undated (Box 23, Folder 27)
    - The Witching Hour (annotated typescript), undated (Box 23, Folder 28)
    - Women who have Big Muscles (typescript), undated (Box 23, Folder 29)
    - Writing as Magic in London (annotated typescript), undated (Box 23, Folder 30)
    - Untitled Essay Fragment (1 of 3) (typescript), undated (Box 23, Folder 31)
    - Untitled Essay Fragment (2 of 3) (typescript), undated (Box 23, Folder 32)
    - Untitled Essay Fragment (3 of 3) (annotated typescript), undated (Box 23, Folder 33)
  - Notebooks, undated
    - 10 Years Ago Dia G., undated (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Anglo-Saxon Culture is a Culture of Shit (multiple works), undated (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - The Beginning of Writing (multiple works), undated (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Being in 1. Earth/Dirt, undated (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Chart: Tarot-Voodoo Correspondences, undated (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - The End of Childhood, undated (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Girls on Earth, undated (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Janey Comes of Age (multiple works), undated (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Jeane Duval (2 notebooks), undated (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - JG Ballard article (2 notebooks and loose notes), undated (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Jung notes, undated (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Late Afternoon 15th 5:00 pm, undated (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - The Levels of Society (multiple works), undated (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - The Making of Ratty Pussy, undated (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Myths for Women/Stories for Women (multiple works), undated (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Nice Girls, Gone Wrong and Nice Girls, Gone Wrong 2 (2 notebooks), undated (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Notes: Leaving the World, undated (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Out of Water Plants Grow, Organs, undated (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Persephone Grow(n)up (1 notebook and loose notes), undated (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Piece for the World Art Class Notes (multiple works), undated (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Rat, undated (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Raw Daddy, undated (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Raw Eurydice, undated (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Raw's Story, undated (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Tales of Revolutionaries (multiple works), undated (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - The Terror Women, undated (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Transforming the Dark Ages, undated (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Ulysses Backward, undated (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Notes-Writings about Acker-Writings by Others, 1979-1997 and undated
    - Notes (in pamphlet): A boy and a girl meet, undated (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Notes: Commonsensical/philosophical use of words, undated (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Notes: I can't do just the dream shit, undated (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Notes: My purpose is to destroy, undated (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Notes: Now she lies here, undated (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Notes: O and Ange, undated (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Notes: On Freedom and Democracy, undated (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Notes (in pamphlet): Somehow the writing eases the pain, undated (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Notes: Subject of conference: virtual body, undated (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Notes: Tracing the Dream, undated (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - Notes: Wuthering Heights, undated (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - Notes: Vocabulary by Metaphors, undated (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - Writings about Acker: Book Reviews, Articles, Essays, 1988-1997, and undated (Box 28, Folder 13)
    - Writings about Acker: Notes by Valentin Viegener, 1997 (Box 28, Folder 14)
    - "Written on the body" Interview by Ros Wynne-Jones in the Independent, 1997 (Oversize-box 1)
    - Writings by Others (not about Kathy Acker) (1 of 2), 1979-1994 (Box 28, Folder 15)
    - Writings by Others (not about Kathy Acker) (2 of 2), undated (Box 28, Folder 16)
- Art Work
  - Dream Map 2, 1977 (Framed-item 1)
  - The Places of Transformations, undated (Oversize-box 1)
  - Blood and Guts in High School: Original art work (minus dream maps) (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Blood and Guts in High School: Art work (color copies) (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - A Map of My Dreams from Blood and Guts in High School, 1997 (Oversize-box 1)
  - The Book of Correspondences and the Journals of Kathy Acker (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Comic book strip for Dennis Cooper (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Empire of the Senseless: Original art work (1 of 3) (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Empire of the Senseless: Original art work (2 of 3) (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Empire of the Senseless: Original art work (3 of 3) (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - I Dreamt I Was a Nymphomaniac!: Imagining: Negatives (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - I Dreamt I Was a Nymphomaniac!: Imagining: Layouts (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - In Memoriam to Identity: Original art work (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Scorpions: Art work (black and white copy) (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Pussy, King of the Pirates: Original art work (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - "Hairs on our Tails, We Pirate Girls" art from Pussy, King of the Pirates, undated (Oversize-box 1)
  - Artaud's The Suicide of my Sister, undated (Oversize-box 1)
  - "Those Oxford Monks" art from Pussy, King of the Pirates, undated (Oversize-box 1)
  - "Song of the Dogs" art from Pussy, King of the Pirates, undated (Oversize-box 1)
  - Grandes Esperances, undated (Oversize-box 1)
- Correspondence
  - 1970-1989 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - 1991-1997 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Undated (1 of 2) (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Undated (2 of 2) (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Barbara Baracks, 1974 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Jim Brodey, undated (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Gerhard Falkner, undated (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Harry Lehman, Jr., 1976 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Larry McCaffrey, 1990-1994 and undated (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Charles Shaar Murray, 1996 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Alan Sondheim, undated (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Justin Wade, 1993 and undated (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - WM, 1986 (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - R. Wurlitzer, 1976 and undated (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - Lafayette Young, 1978 and undated (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - Nancy Kosenta, undated (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - John Martin/Black Sparrow Press, 1972-1973 (Box 30, Folder 17)
- Audiovisual resources
  A portion of the audiovisual resources in this collection have not been digitally preserved. Audiovisual resources that do not have digital preservation files associated with them require digitization prior to use. Contact Research Services for further information.
  - Kathy Acker and British astrologist discuss her astrological chart, undated; Total running time: side one 00:31:31; side two 00:31:27
    - Original audiocassette (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00011-CS-0001)
    - Preservation WAV audio file, side 1 (Digital-materials RL00011-SET-0001, Audio-file RL00011-CS-0001_01.WAV)
    - Preservation WAV audio file, side 2 (Digital-materials RL00011-SET-0001, Audio-file RL00011-CS-0001_02.WAV)
  - Tape from Kathy Acker's answering machine, undated; Total running time: 00:06:30
    - Original audiocassette, side 1 only (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00011-CS-0002)
    - Preservation WAV audio file (Digital-materials RL00011-SET-0001, Audio-file RL00011-CS-0002_01.WAV)
  - Kathy Acker with Nox: Love, Emily. Text from Kathy Acker's book "My Death, My Life, by Pier Paolo Pasolini." Soundtrack: Nox., 1987; Total running time: 00:15:18
    - Original audiocassette (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00011-CS-0003)
    - Preservation WAV audio file (Digital-materials RL00011-SET-0001, Audio-file RL00011-CS-0003_01.WAV)
  - Kathy Acker and an art critic walking through an Andy Warhol exhibit, discussing Warhol, Pop Art movement, undated; Total running time: 00:41:56
    - Original audiocassette (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00011-CS-0004)
    - Preservation WAV audio file (Digital-materials RL00011-SET-0001, Audio-file RL00011-CS-0004_01.WAV)
  - German radio show about Kathy Acker's work. Note: in German; narration about/by Kathy mixed with complete rock songs (artists listed on side 2). Side 2 also contains unrelated radio show that follows the Acker special., Total running time: side 1, 00:31:27; side 2, 00:31:27
    - Original audiocassette (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00011-CS-0005)
    - Preservation WAV audio file, side 1 (Digital-materials RL00011-SET-0001, Audio-file RL00011-CS-0005_01.WAV)
    - Preservation WAV audio file, side 2 (Digital-materials RL00011-SET-0001, Audio-file RL00011-CS-0005_02.WAV)
  - Lecture by Kathy Acker on Maurice Blanchot (La Communaute Inavouable), Emily Bronte's Wuthering Heights, and literary tradition., Total running time: side 1, 00:31:29; side 2, 00:42:23
    - Original audiocassette (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00011-CS-0006)
    - Preservation WAV audio file, side 1 (Digital-materials RL00011-SET-0001, Audio-file RL00011-CS-0006_01.WAV)
    - Preservation WAV audio file, side 2 (Digital-materials RL00011-SET-0001, Audio-file RL00011-CS-0006_02.WAV)
  - Strange Gaze, interview with Anton Corbijn, 1996
    - Original audiocassette (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00011-CS-0007)
  - The ReAN Process, 1995
    - Original audiocassette (Box 33, Audio-cassette RL00011-CS-0008)
- Photographs
  - Photographs of Kathy Acker and others, undated (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Black and white photographs of Acker by Jo Mazelis and Marcus Leatherdale, 1988 (Oversize-box 1)
- Legal Documents
  - Blood and Guts in High School: Banned book documents, 1984-1989 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Clayton Street, SF tenant documents, 1990-1994 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Contract for Time Capsule Project, 1995 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Divorce decree, 1993 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Durable power of attorney for health care conditions, 1997 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Motorcycle insurance policy, 1988 (Box 31, Folder 7)
- Financial Documents
  - Financial documents, 1994-1997 and undated (Box 31, Folder 8)
- Ephemera
  - 1990-1996 and undated (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - You are on the enemy list of The Black Tarantula, undated (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Art work by others, undated (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Class notes, undated (Box 32, Folder 2-3)
  - Contact list, undated (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - LambdaMOO documents, 1996 (Box 32, Folder 5)
- Printed Materials, Research, and Publicity
  - The New Gothic event poster featuring Kathy Acker, 1991 (Oversize-box 1)
  - Natal charts, undated (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Mekons with Kathy Acker, Pussy, King of the Pirates promotional poster, 1996 (Oversize-box 1)
  - Blood and Guts in High School Plus Two Picador promotional poster, undated (Oversize-box 1)
  - PR/Promotional materials, 1974-1997 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Acker's Copy of Virgil's Bucolics and Georgics, undated (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Pamphlets from Acker's collection, undated; 7 items (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - The Re-A.N. Process, 1995 (Box 32, Folder 10)
    Audiocassette RL00011-CS-0008 removed to Box 33.
  - Research material: Blood and Guts in High School, undated (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Research material: The Purloined Letter, undated (Box 32, Folder 12)
- Jeff Goldberg Collection of Kathy Acker papers
  Jeff Goldberg is a friend and collaborator of Kathy Acker. These materials consist of postcards and letters from Acker to Goldberg as well as materials related to the estate of Acker's mother, Claire W. Alexander.
  - Postcards and letters, 1979-1981 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Legal Documents, 1979 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Book Production Materials for I Dreamt I was a Nymphomaniac Imagining, 1980 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Distribution statements and review clippings for I Dreamt I was a Nymphomaniac Imagining, 1981 (Box 34, Folder 4)